driving so this is completely random and
the divers will dive in the random order
selected by a computer and then of
course compiling the results at the end
of the contest today the reverse order
of the top 18 will go through into the
semi-final so the best diver from the
prelims will dive last tomorrow now as
opposed to the sinker you may have seen
there are no 2.0 dives here we start at
3 and we never go a little bit down
about 2.9 but it's always in the 3 rate
ratio or a little bit higher yeah that's
right the the females will perform 5
dives from 5 different groups the
different groups in diving are forwards
which is speaks for itself and backwards
which also speaks for itself the inward
group is where you stand backwards and
spin forwards towards the diving board
and the dangerous reverse group is where
you actually walk down the diving board
forwards landing on the end and then
jump away spin backwards towards the
diving board the final group that you'll
see today is the twist which is really
your rotating along the longitudinal
axis as well we will explain as you go
along
first I've were about to jump on the
diving board there and of course there
was no synchronized judges here today
it's all execution seven execution
judges the two highest and two lowest
marks are taken away to leave the three
remaining scores those are multiplied by
the degree of difficulty and that gives
you the total for the dive so we're
ready to get underway first diver is
from Australia Charlene Stratton
fifth of the world's last year 7th in
Beijing four years ago and that opening
dive will be a forward two and a half
summer sorts with one twist performed in
the pike position remember top 18 will
progress to the semi-finals tomorrow
oh very nice charlie
disappointed not to be on the podium
after the three metre synchro she's a
formidable diver in her own right and
that is a sensational start but this 25
year old Australians campaign beautiful
entry into the water of course the judge
is looking for the vertical entry
without any splash and that didn't look
too far away to me very good start there
anything over 70 points is huge great
start there for the Aussie yeah 72 will
do nice start for the 24 year old
Australian now from Germany again
forward two and a half some sorts of one
twist it's the semifinals in Beijing
catch your dick off nice solid opening
round tie from catch a very experienced
one of the older females in the contest
to date will be relying on that
experience to get her through this Paula
Murray safely and if she continues with
the next four dives and the same
standard as this opening dive then
she'll be assured of a place in the top
18 again here's the one and a half
somersaults eye into the one twist and
then folding over back into the water
it's a lot to get in in this time the
coach has seen happy nodding their
seventh across the board not quite as
good as the opening day we saw from
Charlene Stratton worth 63 points
according to the judges and she goes
into second the big roar greeting the
first of the British competitors sites
differential in the diving style for
this one in words two and a half
somersaults in the pipe position for
Hannah Starling of Great Britain
Oh unfazed the young seventeen-year-old
youngest competitor in this contest
obviously friends and family they're
waving and cheering her on talent
identification program found this little
rough diamond and here she is at 17
years old performing the inward two and
a half in the pike position is her
opening dive
she'll be pleased without men finishing
a little bit low on the water not quite
having enough room but that's a solid
start
well done Hannah yeah good see a smile
on her face she leaves as quickly over
their coach to see what went wrong she
probably does know what went wrong
didn't go too far wrong 60 on the board
for opening dive now another debutante
in the Olympic Games is Marianna furrow
CA France in wood two and a half again
we're tuck we are a little bit of a
small basic simple dive is filled the
inward two and a half so where you're
standing backwards spinning forward
towards a diving board this time opting
for the Tuck position so bending at the
hip and at the knee holding on to the
shins swinging the arms up and over the
diving board squeezing into that Tuck
shape all looks good is very neat and
very tidy it is a lower degree of
difficulty only 2.7 and that gives her
50 6.70 March by the way some people in
America thought you were Welsh the other
day and let some friends are watching in
in the US said you're working with the
Welsh one apparently there you go hey
comes Francesca della pay of Italy and
it is back up to 3.0 degree of
difficulty on this inward two and half
somersaults with Mike
or a beautiful start obviously riding
high from a performance already this
week in the three metre synchro with
their partner tanyaconnor otto who is
also in this competition
Francesca they're very strong needs to
be this is a tough dive beautiful Pike
shape I couldn't see any gap in between
the thighs and the chest there we are
look at that super slow motion taking
off the diving board their safe distance
away clean entry into the water good
start
69 for de la Paix puts her for the time
being into second place course they
first are five rounds of dives
yes Anastasia Wozniak of up and she is
going for two point seven back down the
tariff total and this is an in words two
and a half seven sorts with tuck or just
letting the time we're all over vertical
they're opting for a lower degree of
difficulty this is two point seven all
the girls of course will perform an
inward today which is that we stand
backwards spin forwards towards a diving
board just coming out of her dive a
little bit late there and as you see on
the replay over a vertical that's only
going to get sevens and Alice Tate is
normally up with the aches and eights
and nines so some work to do
yeah doctored and the alarms really this
early four to nine point four zero is
not a catastrophe by any means but not
the greatest of starts from Wozniak Eva
now there's Nora submission scape of
Germany again we're sticking down the
lower end of the tariff range with a in
we're two and a half we tuck
oh if she was a little nearer to the
diving board still a safe distance
interestingly enough all the girls
performing an inward it seems to be one
that most people are comfortable
starting with a bit of a double Banks
they're taking your feet off the diving
board before she's actually taken off I
don't know the judges probably won't
penalize for being too near I wouldn't
want to see it any closer to the diving
board than that the Tuck position is
actually easier than the pike position
you've got less you know less to get
around it's easier to make the dive and
complete the dive so that's why some
girls choosing the tucked over the pike
59.4 zero are the totals will remind you
and recap on how those marks are arrived
at later now he comes the bronze
medalist from Shanghai last year able
more beautiful already a medal in the
bag says oh and I'll cheer the coaches
they like it needs to be solid this is
the first one we've seen today a
backward two and a half somersaults miss
Jennifer just under super slow-mo here
we go swinging the arms good distance
from the diving board beautiful Pike
shape knows exactly where she is
watching where she's been rather than
where she's going and lands on her head
eights across the board good work very
good work indeed puts her joint first
two with Shayan stratton after the first
round so far now Anna Lindberg
surprisingly had a very poor words last
year doesn't make it beyond the pre
level she we wanted to put things right
here here's a back two and a half
somersaults in the pike position 3.0
degree of difficulty
again a veteran of many many Olympic
Games an exceptional diver always on the
springboard otherwise Olympic medalist
fathers one of the the judges here not
judging this competition but Matt's
Limburg is one of the judges one of the
FINA judges back two and a half in the
pike position straight up and down
consistent as you would imagine from
Anna and what she was hoping for to open
her campaign good could you see the
super slo-mo cam there showing the
strain on these divers faces because
they have to five more times or four
more times today and then their cost ten
more times if they get through to the
final that's the mark there for her now
Christina Lucas of America at her
opening round dive is a back two and a
half summer sorts with pike in with the
3.0 degree of difficulty or such a
powerful diver excellent elevation from
the diving boards all about timing
look at this depression here on the
diving board waiting for it to flicker
back up look at the elevation toes above
the five meter board has to come out of
the dive very early cruising this is
what we see the Chinese divers doing
Christina here making that dive very
very easily and controlling it look at
that h2 across the board seventy two
third seventy-two of the competition so
we have joined first place in the first
round now on to the Mexican yes is Laura
Sanchez sort of with an inward two and a
half somersault with Mike 3.0 degree of
difficulty all just letting the entry
there roll over vertical remember the
judges are looking for the vertical
entry without any splash the dive itself
was the aerial work was excellent here
we are right over the timing board
moving away a safe distance making the
time a little easier than she was
expecting to rolling over a vertical
throwing up a little bit of splash
that's gonna cost her a little bit from
the mark on the marks from the judges
yeah 10th place for the time being for
Laura Sanchez Soto 57 the total mark
now he can was Wendy yeah that's a
nickname dang it Yan Yi of Malaysia and
she's gonna open up with an inward
two-and-a-half summer sorts with Pike
again she can see on your screen three
point zero degree of difficulty oh wow
little pocket rocket that dive can
sometimes be quite incredibly
challenging and she's making easy work
of that look at this up up and away
quite short which makes it easier in the
pike shape just a twisting as she went
in the water there the judges won't
won't get the benefit of the replay but
maybe one or two would have picked them
up be interesting to see what the marks
are on this yeah one of them did judge
number two certainly saw the twist in
the water yeah she was a long way to the
side of the board when she landed there
wasn't she's 60.00 for egg in joint
seventh placed a very experienced
competitor is Tanya Kenyatta from Italy
in this position many times back two and
a half somersaults with Mike Ling gambit
for this experienced Italian Oh
beautiful dive that's the dive of the
contest so far we are in its early
stages Wow
Tanya missing out on a medal a few days
ago we'll be looking to to feature in
the podium but she's got a few days to
wait yet but my goodness if she
continues to dive with the kind of form
she's been showing in trainee she'll
certainly be a challenger one to watch
over the next three days Leon Taylor and
judges in accord 75 is the best mark
we've seen so far which puts her in
first place above Abel Lucas and
Stratton on to another Malaysian which I
saw one hiccups another Chong with an
inward two and a half soy sauce with
taka says she's going back to the 2.7 s
nice comfortable start or so you would
think anyway for her in round one all
playing it a little bit safe needed to
be better than that only 22 years old
leaving yourself a little bit more to do
on the next four dives the takeoff is
good notations all good chin in towards
a chest over a vertical six six and a
half probably and two point seven needs
to be a little bit better than that
two point seven and two point eight and
there's quite a few those sprinkled in
here surely puts you behind the eight
ball in tempting qualification why would
you do that well you don't want to go
for broke
well if you make a mess of a three point
zero then you're not gonna be anywhere
near the pace it's a very risky business
anyway of diving so it's not risk averse
is it here we go with Cassidy Krug and
we're two and a half three point zero
I've seen this before in the plank
position more beautiful Wow okay you can
crack a smile if you aren't mr. coach
but wow I was very very impressed been
watching this girl in training looking
for height up on the diving board and
she has got that in abundance that's
going to get eights for sure and yeah
ideal start there for Cassidy
so what judges think of that yeah
they're quite happy with it
she should be two seventy three point
five zero put into second behind
Kenyatta at the stage of round one
there's that buzina of Russia yeah same
with two and a half again a little bit
of a twist on the entry into the water
the dive other than that was almost
faultless so it's a beautiful diver long
lines great lines into the water I don't
know whether we can see on the replay
here you could just see both of her calf
so she goes in beautiful toe point look
at that this is what diving should look
like you could just see they're both
over the feet as she went in which means
she's twisted and that doesn't well
let's see come on judges oh they missed
it okay no need to be personal at
aventure Chavez muñoz ready to go
already with a forward two and a half
oh she was hanging ten which means all
ten toes off the end of the diving board
this is you know this is why lots of the
girls deciding not to start with a
hurdle step here we go let's look at
this on the replay uh-oh
all ten toes over the end tipping
forward with the pallets just so well to
manage to complete the tie without
landing completely on her face well what
an unfortunate start just shows how
difficult these dives are 22.5 ouch yeah
and that could also end her chances of
making the 18 that are required to go
through to the next stage already her
competition could be over now thing like
that at all this is probably how it
should be executed in we're two and a
half to far away from the diving board
there with Atos this is why this
particular dive can be a bit of a
challenge let's have a look at the
replay to see how close she actually was
I still think it's a safe distance here
we are in word spinning forwards towards
a diving board their toes aren't that
far away are they probably just tipping
over a vertical as well I'm sure she'll
be performing better as we go on there
may be a little shaky start there from
the already Olympic champion so far this
these games tipping over a vertical as
you can see I just spotted that look at
these marks eight will count towards
that total of 72 change sometimes I
marked up on this kind of diamond with
two and a half some sorts for the
opening dive for Elena Feder over over
Ukraine all struggling a little bit
there Elena this is a difference bob was
asking me about their difference between
tuck and hiked if you're gonna do the
pike one 43.0 you need to be able to
make it and you can see here Elena is
struggling a little bit she's running
out of room toes aren't too far away for
the diving board chin tucked in towards
the chest because she wasn't quite I
didn't have enough room that's only
gonna get four and a half five yeah
that's not good should have done it
tucked maybe now she knows she'd know at
the time when she put a list of dives in
they fed her over
near the bottom than the top after that
first round I've just laying Castillo
Suarez for Venezuela for two and a half
with one twist in a 3.0 degree of
difficulty to start off her program all
very nice entry into the water the RIP
entry the reason it's called the RIP
entry is when you're close to it it
sounds like you're chairing the water
apart and splashes entry is exactly what
the judges are looking for a little bit
back from the end of the diving board
here isn't quite as much spring there
and when you toes on the end but you
don't want to be right over the end a
little bit to the corner there's the
twist
after the one half somersaults
completing the two and a half
somersaults she was a little bit here
and there in the air and so the churches
have gone yeah mixed bag here and there
and everywhere 60.00 yes her total mark
Wow you know that Chinese is moving ship
and she's gonna open up with that same
dive favored by the majority of the
thirty divers here either in Pike or
tuck position in which two and a half
where 3.0 or no mistakes from Wu already
triple Olympic champion in the three
metre synchro event she's got a silver
and a bronze to boot in the individuals
looking for medal number six over these
well in the final in a few days time and
if she dies anything like that then I
can say for certain she will be a record
breaker or a record equal er actually in
women's diving beautiful dive from Wu
will indeed seventy eight point zero
zero mines of 8.5 s count towards at
total of 78 which puts her in the lead
now second Olympic Games for Rebecca
gallantry and they comes that dive again
see how the other Britain's second of
them does with this
oh it's pretty tidy in the air the entry
into the water looked a little bit
apprehensive if I'm honest she needed to
be a little bit more or confident that
she went into the water or the hardware
works great up here's the one and a half
somersaults there's the one twist
everything looks good but just rolls
into the water there without
straightening out perfectly for that
vertical entry cameraman struggling to
keep up there with all the twists and
turns rolling into the water so the
judges will penalize for that still
steady
yeah it's steady enough 63 is okay no
alarms really for Rebecca gantry with
her opening dive and his men Scout of
Ukraine backward two and a half soy
sauce all just taping over from vertical
as she went in maybe losing her balance
a little bit as she takes off from the
springboard do you lean too far back the
springboard or flip your feet up a
little bit too quickly so as you can see
here letting go of her legs probably a
little bit late and there she goes over
she goes in fact timber okay not very
straight in terms of where the dive was
going she was nearly into the front row
of the audience there for forty nine
point five zero for miss Metzger and
this would work to be done if she wants
to make the top 18 for tomorrow Fanny
Bouvet of France just a 2.4 degree of
difficulty from funny she is one of the
youngest competitors at 18 years old
forward two and a half in the pike
position normally the girls are doing
three and a half's so this is only two
point four it needs to be very very good
I think that's only going to get six
sister sevens which means she'll be off
the place I would not expect her to to
make it through with this low degree of
difficulty but what an experience 18
years old first dive for Fanny and
that's the marks that she has accrued
now that was rather crude to Jennifer
Benitez for Spain the only Spanish diver
here on a team of one there were two and
a half somersaults
Oh a little bit shaky I'm sure there's
plenty of nerves jangling out there
today team of one a thick heavy Xavier
Ilan Oh being the men's as well but
certainly the only female Spanish diver
here in word two and a half seems to be
moving ahead of mind a little bit there
causing her to tip over a vertical yeah
that's a shaky start she's been looking
for something a little more solid to
keep her in the game
well the marks account there are the six
is to 4.5 disappears from the screen and
doesn't get included in her marks
Juliana Veloso our Brazil the much tried
and tested forward two and a half with
one twist a little bit the entry into
the water is what this a bit the let it
down I think she needs to be a little
bit higher on this die so I'm swing or
looks okay here maybe she does the twist
first and then squeezes in not quite
enough room on the end there
so she'll only be getting five and a
half six is thirty one years old oldest
competitor in this contest plenty of
experience so maybe she'll bounce back
well she knows how to but she's gonna
have to with that forty nine point five
she's already about ten fifteen points
has drifted where she needs to be JL
Patrick of Australia and her
self-composed taking a bit more time
than some of the others divers have done
so far backward two and a half summer
sorts of with pike
yes that's really really good
both Australians they're coming out
looking to stunt their authority and the
business end of the field and that's
where you need to be remember the divers
will dive in reverse order as they go
through into the semi-finals jl marking
her campaign opening her campaign I
should say with a very very solid 3.0
back two and a half pint solid is the
word 67 point five zero takes her into
ninth place nor Obata
I repeat that for you nor a barter of
Hungary with first round dive and again
she's gone down to the 2.7 s so it has
to be pretty good you know in the mix
I'm taking your time composing yourself
on an inward two and a half somersaults
we're talking deciding to play very very
safe this morning and just noticed her
second mount dive is actually a very
very low degree of difficulty I guess is
you're playing game of tactics so opting
for the Tuck position here bending at
the knee in at the hip holding on to
those shins it's good seven and a half's
I think two point seven maybe the Pikes
a little bit too challenging for at 3.0
so game of tactics so with the tariff
being so low 56.7
well not maybe the most you could have
hoped for but probably what she was
expecting there's very few divers in
this event who have more experience than
Emily Haman's and she's up next for
Canada born in Belgium that's one thing
I didn't know about it till today and
she will go with an inward two and a
half some sorts of attack again opting
for the safe option straight off yeah
safety first and emily has extremely
long legs and so that makes anything in
the pike position very very challenging
so because your toes come quite close to
the end of the diving board when you do
this dive in the pike emily deciding to
keep in the Tuck position is a beautiful
dive it'll get eights and it's only 2.7
but that will keep her you
well over 65 points and that's where she
needs to be pretty much in the middle of
the pack yeah things that could still be
improved bond with her die of course
they all could be nice you get perfect
tens sixty seven point five zero as we
get to our last competitor and that's
flora GaN dose of Hungary two point four
forward two and a half with pike oh it's
very very precise very neat and tidy but
it's only two point four so only twenty
years old
this young lady first Olympic Games not
much of her to push the springboard onus
and you normally see that kind of frame
on the platform a beautiful smooth entry
into the water
seven seven point five yep yeah because
because it's so low in degree of
difficulty fifty two point eight is all
she can muster and that completes the
first round of the women's 3-meter
springboard can see preliminary to give
us 218 for tomorrow's semi file well
they're surprised at the top of the
table some very experienced competitors
whoo Kenyatta and Abel in one two and
joint fourth and Alipay in eighth Emily
Haman's in night so experience does
count for something in this kind of
competition so there or the moment quite
safe as they are on that page and
Starling is in there as is Rebecca
gallantry so both of the Brits are in
the top 18 at the moment Laura Sanchez
Soto if we stop now would not be and
applies to all the rest on that page and
I'm sure Chavez munos a really good
opening effort finds herself pretty much
a drift of the rest of the field
on to round two of the women 3-meter
springboard preliminaries and we're
watching in the australian charlene
Stratton 7th in beijing good opening
diver 72 can she back it up with a back
to and our summer sorts with pike
getting going for the 3.0 degree of
difficulty option yep she can back it up
okay I've mentioned previously the girls
you know don't need to be lighting this
place on fire they can save that for the
final which is not tomorrow but the day
after you're looking for a consistent
steady performance landing on your head
as we say in the diving world and that's
exactly what Charlene's doing they're
landing on her head 7 7.5 67 good enough
72 backed up with a 70 60 7.50 for
Charlene Stratton catch your dick off
with a second round dive low degree of
difficulty as well Ford three and a half
some sorts you might think with them
that rather complicated explanation
there'd be more than 2.8 but here she
comes in the tuck position yet lots
going on and lots can go wrong you've
already seen some of the divers opting
for only a forward two and a half this
of course an extra rotation extra
difficulty here we go let's count them
one two three and a half looking at the
water doesn't quite get her hands
together as she goes in you can see
they're landing in a handstand did diver
you need to be grabbing hold of a hand
to punch with a flat hand into the water
but it's steady enough to point eight
though Leon seems quite complicated for
a 2.8 to me yeah yeah it is it's just a
high degree of difficulty than the two
and a half which is only two point four
but some of the girls opting from
forward three-and-a-half piked which is
difficult and look what were watching
now hammer Starling three point one
first so we've seen of the above three
dives today and she's going for a for
three and a half with Pike first a
really tricky one
we've seen fanless darling oh yes
beautifully done tipping over vertical
marginally if she goes into the water
but this seventeen-year-old youngest
competitor betting big here today in
front of the home crowd and they
certainly like it here we go forward
three and a half in the pike position
hangs on just a little tip over I think
she'll get six and a half for that look
at this
working the diving board there is all
about rhythm good effort
second round dive and that's what I
can't like to see certainly with
youngsters suppose it's the impetuosity
of youth isn't it they're gonna go for
bigger scores if they can and Hannah has
done that with the sixty point four five
marion Lussier is working her way up the
standings with 2.8 on this forward three
and a half with tongue oh she was a
little bit ambitious there on her exit
of the dive so the come outs as we would
call it in diving where you are moving
from the position to the entry and she
decides to come out just a little bit
too early let's have a look here let's
go there point the toes towards the
swimming pool and that is too early and
therefore ends up short on the dive
we'll only get four and a half so I
would imagine for that and yeah I think
we'll see her back tomorrow the way
things looking with those marks 42 and
we should go I have to do a lot of
picking up in her the rest of her
program is not terribly difficult
there's another three point one
Francesca dollar pay we've seen how a
starling do a three point one yes her
version of the for three and a half of
Pike oh well done I say well done
because she was actually a little bit
back from the end of the diving board
which you'll see on the replay which
makes it even more difficult so not only
is it three point one you can see her
mouthing something to a coach a little
bit but from the end so she would have
taken a sharp intake of breath as I did
here in the commentary box but that's a
really good dive I'll get close to 70
points and that's all you need that's
what you need in this bloomer if you're
going close to 70 points you're going to
be in the business end of the field
conformation in
is around about the seventy sixty nine
point seven five three seven point five
for Francesca Donna pay of Italy and I
stays yeah yeah come up 2.8 live into
the three range yet for her with a for
three-and-a-half somersaults we've seen
that before but now the pike this time
there's one in the tuck position just a
little bit short of vertical as she goes
in it's all very neat all very tidy but
of course the judges you know the marks
are weighted towards the entry into the
water
beautiful toe point very aesthetically
pleasing in a diving clean and tidy
shapes you can see just short of
vertical there so that will cost her and
of course it's only two point eight
degree of difficulty yeah it's gonna put
a bit further behind from where she was
it says forth for time being but so
she's in the early stages of the second
round
very not gonna help her chances are
progression Nora schinsky 3.1 for her
now with the for three and a half it's
it's okay and it's a big it's a big risk
of course going for the three point one
because it's a tough tough dive does a
reasonable job here squeezing into that
Pike shape actually bending a knee
slightly the judges do not get the
benefits of the replay this has been a
little bit cheeky trying to squeeze the
dive in its low finishing on the water
but it's okay
singer marks mmm fifty five point eight
zero I'm sure she is okay she played a
little bit down on where she wants to be
nice young lady was 16 when she made her
Olympic Debbie and Beijing able going
for that one for three and a half again
with Pike now in contrast to the diver
before her Noah from Germany Jennifer
little smart looks like she's got
spring-loaded legs because she just pops
up out of the diving board into the into
the spin on this one let's have a look
at the replay look at the elevation here
up above the five meter board in the
background cruising the dive a little
bit over former vert
she went in but yeah cruising very
impressive coach is never happier though
there's always something but writing in
these she can because sixty six point
six five is decent mark room for
improvement that Alan Lindbergh um
Sweden won't give me a chance to tell
you about it she's gonna go straight
away oh that is nice
very very well executed good use of the
diving board so she really starts to get
it going walking down the diving board
there this is more of a jump hurdle
really launching herself into that you
know double feet on the end of the
diving board there to get enough height
in order to make that that's very neat
and very tidy mid-60s on shore still
more to come from this exciting Swedish
diver to about me they're very neat
great idea mid sixties sixty five point
one zero Anna Lindbergh and that lives
her up to fourth place
Christina Lucas don't hold back she says
do everything with confidence if she
does it on this reverse two and a half
yes she does and she was hanging ten as
well toes over the end of the diving
board but she certainly has the
confidence just stays with the technique
look at the toes all over the timing
board there but didn't seem to pull off
because that's very well executed
plunked it on her head little bit over a
vertical but still a this is the polymer
ease she doesn't need to be scoring
nines a little bit of a straddle
position there the judges won't see that
from the side she I think she needs to
see where she's been so she could spot
the dive well-well saved and where she
is at the moment is joint first with
Charlene Stratton is Laura Sanchez Sato
fifty-seven from the first round second
round dive is back two and a half with
Pike 3.0
yep steady on a head and that's what she
will be looking for it's the most
experienced so the Mexican divers in
this contest spinning backwards
squeezing into the Pike shape a little
bit of crimp in the pike there so just a
slight bend in the knees the judges
probably won't see that a real speed the
replays are just for our enjoyment and
for my analysis I hope is making sense
Laura Sanchez Soto 69 better effort than
the first which was 57 rhythmic gymnast
turned diving out of Malaysia for three
and a half with pike all just showing
you how difficult these dives up managed
to get the rotation working for so the
aerial work was good the all-important
entry into the water is what led her
down a little bit back from the end of
the diving board generates enough spin
but just stays with the spin a little
bit too long as you can see tidal wave a
little bit there not quite enough to get
your surfboard tight but probably not
enough for a good score score is 41
point eight five and Aang may be
thinking maybe I can go shopping
tomorrow I don't think I'll be back for
this Tanya Kenyatta just missing out on
the synchro bronze the other day yes her
forward two and a half with one twist Oh
beautiful entry into the water so having
a little bit of this over father there
four-time Olympic medalist in between
the dates up until 1980 but his daughter
looking for that elusive Olympic medal
this is her fourth Olympic Games and if
she continues to dive like that she'll
certainly be challenging but again this
is the prelims so no medals given away
today or tomorrow this is all about
shuffling the pack and near the top is
Miss Kenyatta no she's not near the top
she's at the top with that 72
straightaway Sean goes straight into a
dive I'll tell you about it afterwards
oh he will yeah he being me and there we
are forward three and a half in the tuck
position we've seen it before and that
was a really tidy effort
squeezing into the TUC shape in order to
spin and spin and spin doesn't take long
from takeoff to entry looking where you
going yet nice it's tidy 63/4 john hyung
joong of malaysia and she's up to ninth
place
Cassidy Krug of the USA both her parents
are diving coaches for three and a half
with Mike again 3.10 she was heading
towards the judges a little bit there
but it didn't seem to affect the dive
again very strong both both the American
girls obviously working very very hard
outside of the diving pool she's way
above the five meter there yeah you
could just see probably yeah see look at
this spinning towards the left-hand side
of the screen they're moving towards the
judges be interesting to see whether the
judges penalized or whether they
actually saw that but it's so it's okay
sevens will count 7.5 s and the sevens
with the line through them do not
towards the total 65 point one zero for
Krug there's da buzina
of Russia with her 2.8 for three and a
half very elegant
yeah opting for the the easier option
here only 2.8 degree of difficulty on
the forward three and a half somersaults
in the tuck position but let's just have
a look at the shape beautiful toe point
look how long a feet are in the toes
though it's and then glides out of it
very very pretty
tip the judges are great they always
agree with you Leon they couldn't do
anything else because a sixty one point
six zero it's okay sevens and two points
seven point five in that mix sorry for
this young go up opening dive because it
went rather wrong for a range of showers
when you're so hopefully the back two
and a half with Mike better
oh it does it goes much much better of
course making a complete ever on her
first I've landing but almost missing
the end of the diving port which
fortunately she didn't do but standing
backwards this time in the back two and
a half in the pike position much better
off a little bit well over a vertical as
she went in so the marks reflect that
six-and-a-half she'll be much much more
pleased with that I'm sure Bob 58.50 it
is for her but she has an awful lot of
ground to make up to make the top 18 as
he of China equal fourth after the first
round and here comes her forward three
and a half you'll see it's a lots been
the second round with pike well having a
good look at that before she punches
into the water looking for that rip
entry seems to be able to make the dive
we like much effort but of course that's
the key to this exceptional diving is
making something really difficult look
effortless and that's what her Z is
doing there
it'll get 8 that's the fault Crum of the
diamond board there that's the wheel
that the divers turned in order to make
it a little bit more flexible or not and
her Z there solid dive as you would
expect yep 70 2.85 doesn't quite put her
into first place yet scan yato is in the
lead not waiting for anybody's Feder
over here it's a good job I'm I'm awake
cuz I'd have missed that she was
couldn't wait to get a dive out the way
first round dive wasn't so hot second
mine time is good got some catching up
to do though experienced diver from the
Ukraine squeezing into the tuck shape
they're very very precise on the entry
eights across the board yes yeah didn't
wait for anybody entering that some
people tell you that they're patient
some people feel they need to get into
it straightaway and she did on any gap
between these scores coming up and her
dive now I'll give you a bit more time
to take over the end just layin Castillo
Suarez or Venezuela but again it's a low
tariff dive which has to be absolutely
spot-on
yep well it's it's on her head and you
know one of the only divers on Venezuela
here and she's done very well to make
the make the cut as in the Olympic
qualification cut the World Cup in this
event there are over 50 divers force
only 30 girls here today Olympic Games
is everyone's dream and she's here today
look at the expression that's how much
effort has to go in squeezing in those
knees towards the shoulders clunking it
on ahead there you go
on your head son fifty four point six
zero six point five walk out towards her
total now we'll Ming chef of China
neither after round one with 78 backing
it up with a reverse one and a half
somersaults two and a half twists yeah
it's a very easy dive I say easy that's
just she makes it look easy it's two
point nine so it needs to be very good
some of the girls you know in the twist
group going for the forward two and a
half one twist women showed you're much
more of a classic dive the reverse one
and a half there's a two and a half
twist she throws her arms out to the
side almost into a Y position boom there
you go and then sorts out that entry rip
entry hick on the nines come the girls
seventy eight point three zero the nines
walk out and she goes back to the top of
the pile above cameo toe and her Zee
seen Hannah Starling and Rebecca
gallantry going with her reverse
two-and-a-half with Mike three point
zero degree of difficulty oh it's it's
good it could have been a lot better
though she did all the hard work she
placed her feet towards the scoreboard
which is where they needed to go and
then for some reason GS pulled their
feet whither as she entered the water
squeezing into the Pike shape all looks
good here and they're just tips her feet
over at the last minute and then causes
that little bit of a mini tidal wave a
little bit skew if their judges would
probably penalize for that as well
they have there we go 54 love he worded
skew whiff into the College
sweet monkey that word now future
reference and yeah the grimace rather
the smile there from a Rebecca Gallen
treat and their perseverance can neither
reverse two and a half up to three for
her on the pike Wow she managed to well
a bit of a peculiar technique there I
won't go into it too much and battle you
would buy mechanics but her arms didn't
seem to swing very much at all or in the
right way and they were certainly been
losing a big back arch to get it get it
around well it seemed to work for her
because that's a reasonable effort six
is six and a half so I would imagine
here we go these elegant super
slow-motion shots but and yeah take it
from me that's alright
58.50 for an appeasement scoop course
the year diamond pit used by Ryan Lochte
and Michael Phelps last night to swim
down I didn't see them on the diving
board so Paula Nancy in between their
medal races obviously and they wouldn't
look right in this competition not a
right body shape I don't think forward
two and a half somersaults and one twist
for Bouvet are France oh it's okay again
this is a tricky dive 3.0 this is her
most difficult dive of her program and
she's put it second
so sometimes it's good to get it out the
way here we are one and a half
somersaults we've seen it before one
twist GS running out of room there but
she does manage to just to Mike get it
in in time only 18 years old first
Olympic Games for Fanny Bouvier from
France
I think she'll only be featuring in the
preliminaries Oh Bob six is for fanny 54
exactly and Noah to be back tomorrow
his Benitez are Spain and the female
diver from that country difficulty not
recruit me out much for her two point
eight on this back two and half summer
sorts with tuck
yes I think she has one of the lowest
degree of difficulty lists in this
competition which is gonna make it
difficult for her to make it past these
polymerase the tuck position is easier
than the pike position therefore it
carries a lower degree of difficulty
Jennifer is on a head there though
rubbing her hands in excitement ahead of
this second round dive let's see if the
judges of inputting scores make you
excited
don't you be upset particularly by those
marks but fifty eight point eight zero
probably not gonna help her in terms of
progression to the last sixteen that's
or the last eighteen tomorrow
Jennifer Benitez of Spain that was and
let's go on to junior Novello so our
Brazil and it's a back two and a half
several sorts with Pike for her second
round I 25th at the moment needs a big
improvement to me that last 16 with
three more rounds after this well that's
a little bit better it's she's working
the board a lot before she took off you
could see you know trying to generate a
little bit more energy through the toes
through into the diving board it kind of
worked for and leaning back a little bit
too far making the dive more complicated
to control arching into some kind of
banana shake but she goes in which of
course the judges won't be looking for
any bananas hungry anyway I wish we had
a commentary cam working here we do have
one Miss Ellie it's not linked up to see
some of the movements and Leon Taylor
they were fantastic we've seen time warp
on to jail Patrick almost radiates
forward to and off some sort someone
twists and pike and of course if you do
have any vacancies for a theater as you
man nice from jail very nice strong
Australian women's diving especially in
this springboard yeah big smiles from JL
and that's exactly exactly what back
from the end of the diving board though
that's not where she wants to be but
obviously you know very accomplished
diver so she can make these dives even
with a average takeoff
they average take off as it she did very
well but there she wasn't anywhere near
the end of the diving board yep
jl is up to ninth place with that dive
she should be comfortably through at
this stage anyway so all three more
rounds to go after this
Nora Bart up two point four second round
dive nice nails forward two and a half
summer sorts with pike yeah gamer
tactics going on here often uses two
forward three and a half and often
messes it up so she's she's opted for
the two-point for the forward two and a
half this is very very basic dive she's
got great height they're coming out
early she'll get seven and a half but
you know that's not going to give her a
much over fifty points and so yes she's
so down the bottom end of the pack I
would imagine let's have a look that she
is 21st well not that far down not
actually that far away from the top 18
that score of 54 that's some work to do
for Nora bata hit somebody started on
the platform came down to the three
meter board and really Haman's after
round one she's ninth round two she's
gonna perform again fairly low DD for
her forward three and a half somersaults
the reason for that it's in the Tuck
position yep same is the first round
dive emily has a long legs a very very
long legs in relation to her body which
means anything in the pike position is
even tougher for this young lady so
opting for the tuck which
biomechanically is easier and therefore
carries a lower degree of difficulty but
she's neat and tidy
she will be getting eights on that and
yep obviously a little toe shot there
for those of you that like feet there's
Emily's toes and into the water
I think the nail bars would do a
fantastic trade around here at the
moment 8.0 degree as degree of
difficulty points for Emily havens lifts
her up to 10th with that mark take her
total to one thirty four point seven
zero and finally Florida GaN dose of
Hungary comes
Tucker dive 2.7 inward two-and-a-half
somersaults she also has a nails done
the yeah the cameraman zooming in I
think there's a nail bar in the Olympic
Village and they're certainly cueing man
the corner or so it seems
flora gone dass only 20 years old yeah
it's an easy list easy degrees of
difficulty and I'm sure she's enjoying
her Olympic experience but maybe not
when she looks at the score more
particularly in 50 2.65 that's okay I
suppose on 2.7 and she is 25th she was
23 she dropped a couple of places from
round one to round two now here are the
main movers and shakers after round two
two Chinese in the top three and America
Australia Italy Canada another American
all the names you'd expect to see on the
front page pretty much that
and the Limbourg to just the top of page
two and going through to the series if
things stayed the way they are now
sterling in 14th place and Rebecca
gallantry in 15th missing out will be
anastasiya Pozniak over in 19th and to
catch a dick off his long way down
21 at the moment for the giant because
there are three more round and there's
plenty of marks at stake to be won yet
aren't around three and setting the
target and setting the standard for the
others the other 29 in the women 3-meter
springboard preliminary here charlene
stratton of australia and again at the
top of the range in terms of degree of
difficulty in this competition forward
three and a half summer sorts with pike
before my quite a few other divers in
the second round she's opted to go for
it as her first dive in round three well
it's a magnificent effort opening up the
third round here nods and smiles and
claps from the coaches again all about a
steady list of dives and that's three
out of three for charlene beautiful dive
up lovely young lady as well it was nice
to see her diving accordingly she trains
very very hard the hard works obviously
paying off
so charlene Stratton for the time being
obviously will go into the lead nice
solid bank of score 7267 point five zero
and sixty eight point two zero for her
third round she took off who was ninth
in rome at the world championships in
2009 is in danger of not making the
semi-final here where has to really get
into it to gear backward two and a half
somersaults in the pike position degree
of difficulty for catcher 3.0
not quite clicking into gear as my co
commentator suggested just gear just
bouncing out of its place there in the
box a little bit short vertical as she
enters the water so it is 3.0 it'll
probably get sixty points or there
abouts
yeah a little low on the water will that
help mmm not sure about that sixty is a
score after a fifty point four zero so
she's quite a long way buying the a ball
a star called Starling from Leeds seems
to be enjoy in the moment there Bob
youngest competitor Wow composure look
at the referee looking at the crowd
trying to pick out some faces needs to
think about her dive of course that's
the most important reason why she's here
it's a reverse two and a half summer
sorts with pike 14th after round two
sterling oh it's a superb takeoff
fantastic aerial working just an error
of judgment on the finish there look at
this she's way up in the air just
pointing her toes a little bit too far
up and therefore tipping over a vertical
she needed to be out of that dive a
little bit earlier there's the chamois
I'll explain more about that throwing it
to a coach headwind Yong Yong's if we
were in baseball that would have been
good but we're in diving and she tips
over a vertical still oh what a shame
well the second cricket test between
England South Africa's taking place in
Leeds which is the club that she's from
that was a gun down very well at hitting
Lee now on to the Frenchwoman Marianna
foressi a is moving up to the threes now
it's gonna be a backwards two and a half
summer sorts with pike she's 28 needs to
get moving pretty quickly oh I think
she's only moving in one direction and
that isn't the direction she wants to be
moving in I don't think that'll move her
anywhere but backwards and that was the
backward two and a half in the pike
position seem to be okay until then and
she was just maybe she fell asleep well
judges can't see that from the side but
she went into the straddle position as
she went man they ended up over vertical
no marks of any note anyway forty point
five zero will count yes one of those
kind of days it's not gonna be her day
unfortunately as it could be fair this
woman certainly in terms of
qualification anyway looking nice and
comfortable very solid so far
Francesca della pate of Italy backward
two and a half somersaults Pike position
difficulty 3.0 fine she gets this right
makes you start to think about where she
gonna be tomorrow afternoon I'll be back
here for the semi-finals yet she's
really come on over the past few years
partnered with tanyaconnor Otto as a
synchro pairing and Tonya has been
bringing her on and this girl is so
exceptional diver in her own right
that's probably her weakest one of the
three so far only get five and a half
six is potentially for that because of
the the arch in the back cause she went
into the water yeah a little bit more of
a banana time I'm hot I'm sure no no
whore I am sure I heard a big scream but
she yet she left the board there so I'm
still laughing at your Anastasia boss
yeah cover a backward to allow service
sorts with pike
oh no well Anna stay you're moving
moving her degree of difficulty up and
the quality of her dive down
simultaneously
yeah the expression says it all from the
coach back two and a half in a pike
position letting go way too early
super March losing the legs oh dear oh
dear indeed
I says yeah Pozniak avert he's having a
bit of a poor day forty six point five
zero slips still further down the
rankings time to go and contemplate in
the old hot tub nor at sub schinsky of
germany we have her round 3 dive and
she's opted to go away from the board
there backward two and a half
somersaults with mike 3.0 degree of
difficulty and she is right on the cusp
of qualification seventeenth so
underline that progression with a good
dive here oh that's much better
yep she knew that she had to step up a
gear only in 17th and wants to be a
little bit further in the pack and
that's a good third round dive there
from the German yeah straight up and
dime that will get 60-odd to the early
60s super slow-mo you can see the
expressions on the faces I love it those
great photos online over divers with
some strained expressions on the face
mid dive 63 that's okay
it's not a bad little progression of
dives from the 50s up to the 60s now for
her Jennifer Abel nice comfortable
qualification place at number seven with
a reverse two and a half summer sorts
with pike oh yeah so much power up
technically she's good a little bit the
feet landing on the end of the diving
board there seem to be one foot in front
of the other not quite sure why that was
look you can see that Eagle Eye spotting
that she does a good job and saving the
dive they're given the impression that
she isn't going over a vertical when
actually the rotation was nudging her in
that direction
he likes it and so do the judges yeah
they do
seventeen point five zero the marks that
count the ones without the line struck
through eight and a seven point five
will count towards her total and the
Lindbergh straight into her reverse
two-and-a-half summer sorts with pike oh
well Tanana was a little bit slow on the
rotation and that meant that she had to
play the waiting game reverse two and a
half in the pike position here she goes
beautiful board timing up jumping away
from the diving board there we go
pointing the toes directly up in the air
and she fixes it that'll get sevens
steady steady Eddie wins race or steady
Anna gets into the semi-finals well on
the way two more rounds to go 63s there
for Evelyn Berg from a distance is
telling you exactly where she went wrong
what she needs to do in the future but
she'll be back for tomorrow
tomorrow unless something goes right
untoward in the last two rounds from the
Swede to the American at Kristina Lucas
we're two and a half service walk with
Pike experienced divers taking just a
little bit longer to prepare themselves
for their dives ones were rushing him
tend to be the ones who are not in the
top eighteen at the moment strong
powerful precise everything you need
really really steady solid confident
consistent beautiful pike shape straight
up in time I've seen it better it's
gonna get seven 7s across the board on a
3.0 steady steady steady seven seven
seven and sixty three with the marks
that are probably working out now that
makes 21 times it by three and you get
63 Laura Sanchez Soto
13th after round two it's a reverse two
and a half with pike she's done very
well a little bit back from the end of
the diving boards here we comment on
that quite a lot because it's so
unsteady in as you're taking off on the
springboard if you're not back from the
end especially reverse that means you
have to jump high by moving your hips
forward in order to generate the
rotation and that's why she had some
challenges on the finish of her dive
there as she entered the water a little
bit over a vertical as you can see feet
tipping over back towards the diving
board she saved it okay and stays in
contention
I think judges just about spotted that
they did seven and 6.5 will count
towards her total of 60 now egg of
Malaysia the heavily taped feet back two
and a half and 26 for the moment so if
this goes wrong probably not gonna be
back tomorrow yet probably needs to be
better than that
in order to move up the rankings move up
the field first Olympic Games only 19
she's got massive amounts of potential
and it's a big hard dive you know list
of dives that she's doing she's not
playing it safe and when you're not
playing it safe you're increasing the
risk by increasing the degree of
difficulty
fives and a 6.0 will count towards fifty
two point five zeros kind of resigned
look at her face again yeah okay I
should've done wrong I'm better but
India can yato for three and a half with
Pike three point one degree of
difficulty on this it's a big dive from
Kenyatta
three point one just rolling over as she
went into the water you'll see on the
replays she enters the water letting her
feet go over from vertical yes she did
all the hard work yeah yeah it's all
good tucking your chin in slightly
rolling over a little bit which means
it'll only gets sixes it's three point
one so it's not going to be well it's
not it's not all over that's for sure
but she'll move down the pack because of
that I think she's giving herself
probably enough of a buffer from the its
first few rounds not to worry about that
too much
fifty five point eight zero or can the
other but certainly the weakest of the
three dives so far Jung Hyung chunk of
Malaysia reverse two and a half with
Mike
she is 16th after two rounds oh not so
good from young a little bit ambitious
when she left she was letting go over
legs way too early
obviously the divers on this particular
dive you're watching where you've been
rather than where you're going so she
looks at the water and thinks she's
higher than she is points the toes down
at the water which is way way too early
ends up shorter vertical splash going
away from the diving board there work to
do for you and oh dear
thirty thirty know well that I think the
work has probably already done something
the great day's work for it that's the
krug of the u.s. eight a champagne
performance and Krug on this back two
and a half should probably keep the the
cork in the champagne at the moment a
long way to go yet got to get through
these preliminaries and they're gonna do
it all again in the semi-finals both
Americans here having a good day at the
office
landing on the heads a little bit over a
vertical their six six and a half
probably 3.0 it'll keep over well
maybe move it down slightly but she's
got a bit of a buffer
well the moment quite a few divers still
to go
she is v means a top 18 place he's at
the moment assured
two more rounds though to come after
this there's that buzina of a rush up
was 10th in Shanghai last year back two
and a half summer sorts with pike mr.
dyes are very similar for up many of the
competitors hit
there's her third round dive oh that's
much better
really really classy actually you can
see why she made a final last year at
the World Championships in Shanghai and
even getting a rapturous applause there
from a coach and the Russian coach is
not shown for showing very much emotion
if you're diving well or not but Nantou
is no dead CEO is the only Russian in
the mix at the moment get over 65 I'm
sure and and it stays yet it's got a lot
of work to do 60 7.50
for her up to sixth place at the moment
young lady was in a bit of trouble
because she's possibly the pack it's
probably better known for a 1 meter 3
meter here comes a reverse two and a
half summer sorts with pike on the
slightly higher board well she got a
take off right then the first dive that
she did she was way over the end in fact
she only had half a foot of each foot on
the diving board if that makes sense
this time she landed on the end of the
diving board not quite on the end but
good enough his reverse two and a half
but playing it safe thinking that she
was lower than she was points two toes
up towards the ceiling here we go Surf's
Up this is not gonna make Pleasant
looking for her in terms of marks
talking about four four and four point
five and thirty seven point five zero
will not get it done for a semi final
place for her on to hers eat of China
third place back two and a half summer
sorts with Pike third place China one
and three after run over to she's in
third it's her third round dive
oh that's more like it from her has he
already Olympic champion and looking for
another medal head to head with her
teammate and the rest of the field but
her teammate
whoo we're becoming shortly is it worth
a nine yeah I'd say the judges would
probably go eight and a half nine on
that beautiful here we are squeezing
into that Pike shape finishing by
board-level cruising into the water not
much splash and the biggest mark we have
seen so far today 3.0 degree of
difficulty producing a seventy nine
point five zero dive for her Z they no
filler over who rather rushed her first
two round dives and then get a chance to
tell you much about them backward two
and half somersaults with Pike 3.0
degree of difficulty just about give you
enough time to to tell us what the dive
was Bob there before she left from the
springboard obviously wanting to get
this competition out of the way and
let's see where she is after this cuz
that's a better effort but she's left
herself a little bit too much to do arm
swing generation of the power needed to
leap up squeezing into the pike shape
it'll get sevens which is pretty good
and at the moment up to 12th position so
she's flirting on the margins our
qualification for tomorrow just Lena
Castillo
Suarez in the last qualification place
at the moment eighteenth it's not gonna
help that she's got a two-point eight
dive here two and a half with target
needs to be very Oh what happened here I
can explain that so that is actually a
technical restart the crowd getting
behind it to encourage this and what
will happen now she will perform the
dive the the judges will mark out of ten
as normal but there will be a two-point
deduction from each of the judges for
the restart so I think she stopped
because for some reason she balked out
of balance
here we go attempt number two
oh what a shame it's actually a very
good dive it's technically precise she
would probably get sevens but those 7s
will have two marks taken off so I'll
show you when it comes to screen there
we are finally gets to take off in first
time we've seen a restart here it's a
beautiful dive what a shame
so she was flirting on the edge of the
semi-finals that isn't going to help her
campaign so let's see how does this get
imported by the time I'm not sure what
we see on our display here so the judges
will mark out of ten and then it will be
recalculated okay so those are the marks
but if you see all those marks seven
reads five 7.5 reads five point five and
seven reads five that gives a total of
43 so what we're seeing there are the
actual scores the judges put in and then
the calculation takes place off your
screen a good job I know what I'm on
about isn't it otherwise that would be
really confusing we didn't know you did
maybe I don't
we'll make sure in the lead after round
two it was just emptying the bins when I
came in 150 6.30 accumulated from the
first two rounds and here she goes with
3.1 so she's just upping the degree of
difficulty a little bit forward three
and a half some sorts with pike for the
leader oh not so good from Wu she was
actually over the end of the diving
board which is what we've seen from a
couple of the athletes so far today
makes it very difficult hopefully when
we get around to the replay I can show
you here we go so look at this toes over
the end of the diving board squeezing
into the Pike shape but a little bit low
on the water it's neat and tidy but it
shouldn't really get more than a six and
a half in my opinion but as she's such
an exceptional athlete maybe the judges
will go with her and they do
yeah 7 and 1/7 that's a little bit
higher than it ought to have been
she moves down into second place though
now Rebecca Gallen tree up into the
higher stakes pick your chips if you
like three point one on the you for
three and a half somersaults with pike
15th and the moment and going forward if
she can get this right yes that's much
better for it yeah whoo
struggling a little bit on this
particular dive so Rebecca doing very
well to follow the Olympic champion
here we go squeezing into that Pike
shape plenty of high enough drop time
it's steady it's into the water
seven seven point five so I would guess
and that will help because it's three
point one they like it they like it very
much indeed I do love that dress
probably wouldn't fit me but I do like
it
Rebecca Gavin tree with sixty nine point
seven five three lots of sevens will
count towards her target now Miss Wentz
go ones get things going pretty quickly
and they're getting going quickly oh yes
she is getting it quickly but not in the
right way just attack in the end of the
diving board they're getting into the
dive probably a little bit too quickly
not waiting for the diving board to
throw up in fact she's miles back from
the end running out a room here and
definitely needs a three and a half
meter platform yeah not good from the
second of the Ukrainians we've seen this
morning and she went so quickly I didn't
get a chance to comment on Bob's dress
that he quite likes in the audience just
as Willie is off screen isn't it I did
dress up for today word didn't quite
work obviously now family move a 2.8
where the backward two and a half
somersaults round three dive two point
eight she's not really pushing the boat
out today is she in terms of wanted to
progress almost like she's wanting a bit
of experience for next time she is
getting some here a French girl 27th at
the moment and unlikely to return
tomorrow with tariffs like that
yep I think you hit the nail on the head
there Bob funny very very young the
second youngest competitor here and it
takes a while to build these difficult
dives Hannah Starling from the Team GB
rocking and rolling with the degree of
difficulty Fanny here a little bit easy
on the degree of difficulty entering the
water looks like she jarred a shoulder a
little bit there certainly made me wince
as she went in super slow motion showing
you that the toe point goes into the
diving board in order to generate the
height a little bit short there for the
French girl fifty point four zero for
her second youngest competitor followed
by beneath a snap in there Bob yep
that's Jennifer she wants to get this
competition out of the way not having a
great day in the office today
reverse two-and-a-half in the Tuck
position jumping away from the diving
board squeezing into the touch shape
seem to be rocking and rolling a bit in
the air as if she was steering a bus or
something let's have a look here moving
side to side not quite sure what's going
on there it wasn't particularly neat and
tidy and not having a fantastic three
meter prelim yeah it's more Rafa Benitez
really wasn't a thirty-seven point eight
zero for her and the transfer coming
back tomorrow getting more remote
Julianne Veloso in 29th place with her
reverse two-and-a-half she's plunked it
on ahead yeah and it didn't look his oh
it was gonna be that way she landed on
the end of the diving board with the
toes over the ends which makes it even
more difficult but she managed to stay
with it squeezing into that Pike shape
holding on pointing her toes up and yep
she's straight up and down will she make
it through little way to go she's off
the pace currently time hotel two more
guys to go
fifty-four point zero zero for Giuliano
Veloso and 22nd at the moment Laura seen
Sharlene Stratton to open up here comes
jail Patrick the Australian traversed
two and a half somersaults with Mike
and relying in ninth place nice and
comfy in the middle of the pack oh now
it's all about the c-word the
consistency and jl GS faltered slightly
then we shall leave her a little bit of
work to do on her final two dives looks
good so far squeezing into the pike
shape looking at over a toes just
hanging on a little bit too long in her
Pike position let go now
no now oh there she goes over she goes
didn't hear you obviously fives will
count all three fives multiply it by
three yeah get it now don't ya fifteen
times three gives you the marks and the
ones with the lines through they don't
count that mantra in your head before
the end of the week nor a barter of
Hungary with a back two and a half
somersaults in the top position now she
is not that far outside qualification
here and they have been a few falters
around the 18 to 20 position so she
could make up some ground on this
backward two and a half
we're tuck apart for the fact it's 2.8
degree of difficulty so pretty much has
to be spot on
it does need to be spot on it's very
very low degree of difficulty throughout
all five of her dives she is playing
safe spent many a competition making
mistakes on the higher degree of
difficulty getting frustrated that she
would never make a final or rarely this
is a game of tactics and at the moment
it's going okay I think she'll still be
well there will there abouts in the top
18 Bob how's she looking 17th nor Abaza
so she's up there but she will be
knocked down by Emily hey Mazz I'm short
but she might just have crept into a
qualification place there on to Emily
Haman's not no robotic we just saw her
and it is a 3.0 degree of difficulty
reverse two and a half some sorts for
the Canadian oh what a dive really
showing a class she has won a medal at
the previous four Olympic Games
that is incredible medalist here five
days ago in the Oh
winning contest with Jennifer Abel and
diving like that here we go over 75
points on this one I'm sure beautiful
dive from Haman's yeah Canadian diving
team very close-knit we'll be delighted
by that coach of course always got
something to say about how she could do
it better now the final competitor in
round number three is flora gone dose of
Hungary reversed two and a half
somersaults 2.8 with tongue up straight
up and down she landed on her head which
is exactly what she wants to be doing as
I mentioned previously she's very very
slight and it's difficult to push a
springboard I'm and there's not much of
you this is it's well placed it's low
degree of difficulty it will get over 50
points she's must be enjoying her
Olympic spirit I think she's only 20
years old and she's got a cool main
floor a condos all right that name yeah
can't see you adopting it mind you but
still end of Round three and so looks
China 1 & 2 where we've seen that before
Emily Haman's Canada 3 & 4 Australia
just changing the routine a bit with the
fifth place in Italy - USA that they're
bunching together here aren't they -
Canadians - Chinese - Americans and a
portly from a British point of view one
through one right on the edge & a
starling close she is he going through
Noora bars has just stolen her position
with that dive and anastasiya posniak
over it's still not quite in the top 18
as yet these are the ones who will be in
their own little repechage somewhere
down Stratford Paul
penultimate round starts with the
Australian Charlene Stratton
looks to have done pretty much all the
work she needs to have done to get
through to the last 18 very comfortably
you see on screen fifth and round three
starts for her and for everybody with
the reverse two and a half summer sorts
with pike in Australian in a decent
position with her fourth dive she's hot
to trot yeah the coaches like it again
for steady dies from Charlene 3.0 to
reverse two and a half in the pike
position little bit back from the end of
the diving board whippy on the start
there you can see the big arch at the
beginning she manages to control it okay
on the finish seven and a half I think
coming her way and again it's a long old
competition sixty seven point five zero
that's fine not great but it'll do now
on to the Chairman
we'll see here yeah close-up on the
catcher dick off verse two and a half
somersaults in the plank position and
she is flirting with not qualifying in
17th place after round three oh well
she's flirting with qualifying now
that's the best I've so far round number
four reverse two and a half in the pike
position 3.0 it's a big dive and it's
where it needs to be to put a back in
contention
I think she's 17th currently or after
the round round three that'll put the
pressure on a lot of the other divers in
that kind of middle ground middle of the
pack got to be in the top 18 to make the
cut cut your dick off
yeah like that because smile on her face
happy with it and she might be 7th and 7
points a she all sevens on there let's
give her the mark she needs of 63 all
her chances of returning in the
semi-finals have a starry however didn't
really want to see that because that's
one of the places she was looking for
she can do a lot of good for herself
with a decent or excellent backwards two
and a half summer sauce with pike
well that's good it is good 17 holding
her own halted on the last dive she's
gonna get those claws right now and claw
her way back that's very good straight
up and down little bit of a tip over
it'll get seven and a half so those
should get over over 65 points and that
will bring it back up in the mix well
done good little battle for that final
qualification place going on and Hannah
is part of that battle with sixty 7.50
Marion 48 he's not returning she's 29th
well it's one of her better dives for
two and a half for one twist lots lots
going on generate enough height from
that diving body in order to complete
all these spins and rotations here we go
folding into the pike up i1 twist back
into the pike squeezing in it straight
up and down six and a half so I guess
but too much work to do for the one
first of two French divers yeah
the early tariff dive didn't really help
accumulation 58.50 on that dive has been
in her previous to though Francesca
Donna paid just stepped outside the top
ten after a third round dive
it's not to repair the damage with a
reverse two and a half somersault with
Pike 3.0 through the degree of
difficulty on this one
well she does okay in fact she'll get
away with that I didn't really like the
take off I might go too deep into there
to the technical it but she she kind of
collapsed through her knees and skipped
off the end of the diving board there we
go see the knees were bent there the
churches should penalize for that but
she managed to fix it up okay on the
finish to give the impression the dive
was actually better than it is I
shouldn't think that you see more than
six six and a half bottle been doing the
runes again 6.54 down a peg
anastasiya posniak over 20th place will
not get it done for the semi-final so
she has to find something out this
reverse two-and-a-half somersaults Pike
3.0 well that's much more like it
Olympic medalist next to you Leah pack
Alena in the synchro springboard so she
knows what it's like to stand up in this
kind of an occasion that is much more
like it she does need to get the
comeback going on and that will help her
this dive will add to the previous three
one more dive to go from Nastya
Anastasia nasty it's a nickname in case
you're wondering I was in verse two and
a half in the pike position yeah it's
good let's see less from legal people
arriving you said that 7.54 posniak
Evert and will help her cause quite some
way
Norah schinsky 15th after round three
and here comes her reverse to announce I
was up with Mike oh that's the best dive
she's been relatively solid you know not
really lighting this place on fire but
landing upright each and every dive
consistent they'll get over 65 points
and that's exactly what she needs to
keep her slowly moving up the pack I
think Bob hey won't do her any harm will
it sixty seven point five zero the mark
which we got confirmed on screen just
give me a teaser I shoulda told you
before you see on speed but here it
comes
three sevens at some point fives right
across the board and at sixty seven
point five zero for schinsky Jennifer
Abel so place the world's fourth place
of the Olympics of the moment that is
good I can hear the coaches in my ears
I'm sure you can hear that home shouting
and screaming trying to influence the
the judges need to influence them too
heavily though that's well that's a
little bit low on the water actually not
as strong as I've seen Jennifer perform
this particular dive in the past
Shammi just in the water there explain
what they do in a bit but yeah 63 points
seven seven and seven before Jennifer
able and she did all the hard work early
on and limburger's just moved back into
the top ten so is it a lot margin for
error here
inward two and a half some sorts with
Pike 3.0 for the Swede
it's tidy it's sometimes the one that
lets a dime she's had many an injury and
a bank or in her diving career actually
she is that what she take listed a as in
there's no tape on her ankle
obviously you recovered from those in
injuries in the past and this dive is
certainly a little bit easier than I've
seen it for her in the past
well done Anna what Marx does it bring
it brings another set of 7s judges are
being consistent and so now is she with
a 63 second Olympics for Christina Lucas
of America seventh after round three and
it's three point one degree of
difficulty on a forward three and a half
summer sorts with pike what she was
cruising made a little bit of a mistake
on the entry into the water she done all
the hard work the aerial work is good
here she goes up up and away this is
tough it's three point one squeezing in
just lowering the dive to roll over a
vertical in fact she's probably a little
bit low on the water which can
contribute in that way didn't quite have
the the confidence she needed at the
bottom six and a half stack I'm sixty
point four five is the total score for
Lucas now Laura Sanchez saw top the
Mexican in 13th place after round three
three point one's for you oh that's very
good she she has a little bit of a
challenge on some of her takeoffs I'm
gonna say she looks a little skew if
again there we are pointing slightly
towards the judges spinning towards us
here at home or you at home me here in
the commentary box we need to kind of
push her back that way then we can see
it potentially for the yang landing in
the corner of the diving board spinning
towards us there now there isn't correct
you should be in line with the diving
board Mexican coach there
okay the judges didn't see it no we did
but you didn't judges so that's why
should be marked up slightly on that
sixty six point six five last but one
dive in this competition for egg our
malaysia she won't be returning reverse
two and half somersaults with Mike three
point zero degree of difficulty oh that
feels like a little bit of a bat around
the back of the head
short of vertical not quite looking back
far enough in order to bring the dive
vine to the vertical position here we go
you can't see where you go and you can
only see where you've been and it
doesn't quite make it
Oh little bit doesn't hurt quite as much
as it does from the 10-meter yeah being
thrown here there and everywhere no I
think the coaches in yellow from
Malaysia they're saying all Bob that was
the equivalent of an emergency stop at a
car wasn't it just coming to a grinding
halt there not been a great day for egg
it's been a okay date for ten year
Kenyatta so far see what she can keep it
going with inward two and a half
somersaults in the pipe position back up
there to the 3.0 degree of difficulty on
this one Oh beautiful dive from Tanya
Kenyatta yep she's certainly gonna give
it a wall this will be her chance her
final chance actually in two days time
provided she makes it through to
challenge her a medal to emulate her
father the great diver Giorgio Kenyatta
this year's inward two and a half in the
pike position delicious entry into the
water
YUM
75 for sadly again sure how you respond
to that so I won't I just say that was
pretty good now chong of malaysia where
the back two and a half somersaults with
pike 27th after round three highly
unlikely we'll see much more of her oh
it's neat and tidy and it's not going to
help her campaign this morning twenty
seventh after third round that may move
up slightly it's neat and tidy it'll get
sevens a little bit short of vertical so
that's pretty good if she did Ferb he
performs her first three with that kind
of execution she'd have been a little
bit more in the mix one more dive to
come for her or she can think about the
journey home or enjoying yourself in the
athletes village this 15th place is
gonna go hurtling down as the
competition goes on Casti Krug into a
reverse two and a half very quickly yes
she came hurtling into the end of the
diving board there generating quite a
lot of forward momentum and that can be
a little bit risky because union Nita
put the brakes on and then you know let
the hips move forward as you spin
backwards on the reverse a little bit
scruffy there both feet flat legs coming
apart so it's only gonna get sixes over
a vertical yeah actually started off
strongly no the second American diver
we've seen is gonna be moving down the
pack slightly with 51 points not good
currently in eighth position but again
she won't be there for very long so
you'll probably find herself in the
bottom half of the qualifiers very soon
now desktop buzina of russia reverse two
and a half so again
well that's more like it
there we go contrast to cassidy you can
see the elegance of this russian diver
on this particular dive very neat very
tidy the judges are looking to be
impressed
the beautiful nature of the dive
aesthetically pleasing look at that
beautiful Pike shaped great line little
bit over vertical as she went in that
will get 7.5 s yeah which is much more
like it conformation sixty seven point
five zero seven point five those ones
were counting the ones on the right-hand
side of the screen are struck off
working with a hyperactive child here
comes another one the ranches Chavez
muñoz well it's pretty good see she's
left herself way too much to do after
the the first round I've ended up in the
middle of the pool this one he's
actually good straight up and down
showing her courage and determination
and professionalism by continuing to put
every single bit of effort into her next
round I followed by the next one it's
good it's three point one it's tough
father to see this Mexican girl in
another day but she won't be progressing
today too much to do yeah 22nd at the
moment but that will change with the
remaining divers to come let's diver
however he was looking forward to she
would be I'm sure back tomorrow hers eat
first two and a half summer sorts with
Pike 3.0 oh wow here comes her Z like a
steam train seat very well they're
hanging ten feet over the end of the
diving boards staying calm staying
composed keeping the pilots look at that
almost skipped off there but she knows
what she's doing
kinesthetic feedback knowing where you
are when you're moving all working for
upside down there we go into the water
pretty good that will be good enough for
first place before the time being over
300 goes her seat now on to Elena who's
been involved in diving straight away
yet trying to rattle off these dives as
quick as she can getting through but
that's actually another good my own
effort she left herself a little bit to
do first two round dives not so hot
three and four much more like it
squeezing into the Pike shape
yes sneak it in there that'll get 65 ish
nice and she is moving out the pecking
order you see on the left your screen in
red she's up to 12 play snarling a fella
over that score of 66 such a beautiful
diving pool joseline Castillo Suarez yes
she's in the distance there she is
close-up where the back of two and a
half summer sorts with Pike 3.0 degree
of difficulty no it's pretty ordinary
and you took a time shaking his head a
little bit left yourself quite a lot to
do 22nd it's only gonna get fives on
this short of vertical letting go a
little bit of an arch splitting the feet
yeah lots of little errors there making
it an average dive and that's exactly
what's reflected in the marks from the
judges five five and five as the ones
that will count towards her total score
the second of the chinese wu ming shep
second place after round 4
she comes with her reverse
two-and-a-half somersaults in the pike
position Wow wowee I was expecting that
to be good you have a little bit of
trouble with their takeoffs or landing
on the end of the diving board but no
mistakes there for five dive reverse
two-and-a-half in the pike position from
Wu they still get nines
beautiful exit from the dive gliding in
splash this entry here we go
effortless you can't even see the strain
on her face squeezed against that
beautiful Pike shape drilling her entry
let's go whoo we haven't had any tens of
the counted yet with only tens on the
scoreboard they're quite three lines for
whoo
who goes into first place yeah Rebecca
Gallen treat there's two more round to
go and the way things are standing she's
standing in position to go forward to
the last 18 inward two and a half
somersaults with Pike 3.0 for the second
Brit running out of room well the
take-off looked okay to me but then I
think she just needs to be a bit more
confident that she exits the dive here
we go squeezing into the pike spinning
forwards towards the diving board and
she a co-op she needed a bit more height
in a bit more rotation on that but she
could have still attacked the finish a
little bit more can't really see from
under the water there but yeah that's
not good and maybe she can hang on in
there died to 15th Joe might have a bit
of an agonizing way to find out whether
she's made it that's a brave smile I
mean I confident smile at this stage and
I his men scoop of Ukraine 23rd after
round three yes her in we're two and a
half little bit better than Rebekah
gallantry from Team GP just before her
same dive inward standing backwards on
the diving board the trick is here is to
be far enough away from the diving board
so you don't touch it and when your legs
are straight as the girls are here in
the pike position
you can't come a little bit close to the
diving board but she was a safe distance
but that does compromise the height you
get sometimes in fact to be safe she's
moving right to the side look at that
almost landing on her side as she went
in yeah that's not gonna be all that
advantageous for a 20th place finally
Bouvet now still in the twos 2.8 for the
reverse two and a half oh that's one of
a special efforts this morning 2.8
degree of difficulty squeezing into the
touch shape making sure she completes
the rotations before pointing her toes
up towards the ceiling yeah six six and
a half I think for that
one still I'm sure we see this young
girl featuring 18 years old there we are
well she's up to 21st a few more divers
to go in this round yet so that's a bit
of progress for her from 25th where she
was yes
Jennifer Benitez our Spain and the
wretched last round I'm sushi correct
things forward two and a half yeah it's
good it's reasonable it's well executed
but it's low degree of difficulty two
point four here we go back from the end
of the diving board squeezing into the
pike shape she knows where she is
looking at the water there before she
lines up for it 60s I think but
certainly won't be moving forward into
the semi-finals I don't think obviously
one more round of dives to go after this
one yeah 30 will be cold
- 18 and 18 when we called - 12 for the
final where they after onto Giuliano
Veloso Brazil another one who will not
be in the last 18 which is there
something really incredible in with two
and a half with pike
look here the strain is as she took off
their grunting a little bit like a
tennis player on a return just showing
you how much effort needs to go in and
the grunting worked because that's
actually one of her better dives still
not sure where she's going to be after
this round I excited the top 18 it shows
you how much effort these divers are
putting in a three and a half meter
springboard would have been a benefit
there when that one though
six is and or six singular as 6.5 toward
her total as we move on to the second of
the Australians jail Patrick only 14 so
no margin for error on this for three
and a half three point one oh you gave
me the commentators curse there Bob no
Marty forever and that was nearly a big
error yeah
JL started off strongly you can see
their toes over the end leaning forwards
way too far just up I hides it on the
finish that's only gonna get five so I
think squeezing in I bet she's going oh
no oh no oh no as she comes around here
and I certainly was anyway jail probably
much more composed than I frustrating
but has she done enough oh she's a big
John Lennon fan that's a fifty one point
one five for jail Patrick Nora barter
18th place last of the qualification
places for her butts very type two in
about sixteen and twenty one here so
this is it needs to be good again she's
come for a very low tariff dive try and
submit that place it reversed
two-and-a-half somersaults with tuck for
the Hungarian
Oh game of tactics unfolding going for
Lolo to CRIF difficult it in the
expression on the coach's face s says it
all now nor playing safe universe
two-and-a-half actually kills the
rotation a little bit there by bringing
your knees up off the diving board a
little bit quicker than she needed to -
yeah - almost stopped herself rotating
so quickly and didn't need to do that
and sure - vertical oh my good look at
the damage has been done to that
eighteenth down to 24 for Nora barter
she was looking at the semi-final place
now maybe she is not after that emily
Haman's however a lot of divers behind
her so progression should be a formality
now with her for two and a half with one
twist oh you say formality it's a little
bit of faltering there from Haman's I've
been mentioning throughout a program
she's got long legs in relation to her
body that means anything in the pike
position is tough here we go just
showing you how tough it is there she is
one and a half somersaults into the
twist just running out of room Emily
would have benefited from the three and
a half metre springboard not that there
is such a thing she are squeezing and
I've seen her do that so much better
that will get less than 60 points 58.50
to be precise 6.5 s will count towards
the total that's how we arrived at that
58.5 and last up it is the other
hungarian flora gone dos she has a
chance you know I'm moving into a top 18
place 21st at the moment after round
three get this one right you never know
oh let's go GaN DOS I hope she does make
it through loving a name Wow you know
it's tough out there she's only 20 years
old and it's a springboard and I don't
suppose she weighs very much is he's
having to push this thing down see the
wheel there just left of the shot the
further back you moved that the more
flexibility in the diving board it's
obviously divers preference where they
have that that's it give us a wave floor
I keep on chipping away you know 20th
moved up now
question is who is where and who is
gonna be returning for the semi-finals
we don't of course know that yet we have
one more round to go but who's put
themselves in position front page all
these should be safe I say drop a dive
China China it's the Australia Canada
Canada and top ten pretty much you'd
predict there's any big names who are
struggling a little bit on page number
two because all the big names and the
big nations are they yeah dalla pays on
page tears Cassie Krug the two Brits who
sixteen and seventeen there really is no
margin for error there and jail patrick
has the last position Bosnia cover is
not quite there actually gone just got a
lot of ground to make up to get the top
eighteen she got twenty points to make
up and she's not going to do that I
don't think young was meant to go Bouvet
for though so or thinking about
Westfield tomorrow and some shopping
[Music]
last round they grow up from a great
crowd they have been so noisy in here
and very supportive very appreciative
all the divers particularly those of the
home nation and good succession of dyes
from Charlene Stratton today not really
ever been in trouble 72 67 68 and 67 the
marks the first four rounds as she
finish it all off in style and get ready
and prepared for the last a team she's
going with an inward two and a half
somersaults Pike 3.0 and she's looking
very serene on that three meter board
yeah it's really really steady yeah the
coaches know that she's easily through
the prelims and that's what the divers
are looking to do today smile from
Charlene they're finishing on the inward
two and a half in the pike position as
we know 3.0 this is normally a best dive
and it's certainly there for her today
beautiful entry into the water seven and
a half Sun short steady performance
today from Charlene she will definitely
be in the semi-final tomorrow
well she performs like this in the semi
final she'll be back for the final as
well because that's a really good
collection of dives that she's done
today never really looked in any trouble
at all shiny and Stratton take about and
move on supposed to catch the dick off
food mmm still not quite there 15th is
all right now there's not a lot of room
for manoeuvre if things go wrong inward
two and a half somersaults with Pike
running off her program with a 3.0
degree of difficulty or very good the
pressure was on catcher needed to
respond in order to get through just
making a way to the side that here we go
on the replay squeezing into the Pike
shape looking for that vertical entry
into the water and there it is seven 7.5
s and secure berth into the semi-final
I'm guessing
there's the marks for catch up and we
will see her again in the semi-final six
or seven point five zero now once a
synchronized swimmer now a diver our
Starling is on the verge of a first
Olympic semi final and the
seventeen-year-old Basin leads soak it
all in
she's taking it all in see but look on
her face is quite overwhelming for her
for two and a half summer sorts one
twist in the pike position for Hannah
seventeenth after Round four Oh so to
remind us final won't dive there for
Hannah the youngest competitor and my
goodness you should have heard the
cheers when she just stood on the diving
board then she's smiling and she should
be too though the Union Jack's wow what
a fantastic final dive that's before
she's going look at this really enjoying
the competition is swing in the arms
speeding in there we are
head up a little bit in the twist there
two and a half somersaults vertical
entry in sevens to boots
63 go for a plunge get ready maybe for
tomorrow she's put herself in a really
good position to do that last die for
Marion for Izzy eight it's a reverse two
and a half just short of vertical as she
goes in there hasn't had the best
performance today but only twenty years
old both French girls very young
inexperienced and here in the Olympic
preliminary this is where you get your
big big learnings finishing on one of
her better dives today lots to take away
51 that's where she finishes and
takes her leave as we welcome onto the
board the Italian Francesca dalip 8 this
needs to finish things off here the
forward two and a half somersaults and
one twists and she can bring in that
program all over again in about twenty
two hours time well good strong finish
faltered a little bit on mines three and
four opened up electrically one and two
final dive back from the end of the
diving board again which is Oh making it
so difficult here we go if we ever see
the replay there we go a little bit back
from the end of the diving board
completes the dive well but it could
have been better issues on the end
sevens I think quite a bit of splash at
the end there too which I'm sure the
judges will have noted she knows that's
not quite how she wanted to execute that
but 63 he's okay and would be too many
alarms for her as opposed to this lady
there's one place away from
qualification and the stage yeah
Wozniacki Evert of Russia this needs to
be special or she needed to dig deep and
it's good but I think it needed to be
better to assure her the place you will
have an agonizing wait now to see if
that is good enough it's 3.0 forward two
and a half is one and a half somersaults
there's the one twist and then entry
into the water the toes are pointed at
six and a half's I think she would have
wanted seven 7.50 obviously she'd have
been delighted with higher than that
not into the 60s I think that may just
harm her chances are being back for war
in the semi-finals
Nora schinsky needs to get the job done
here on this forward two and a half and
one twist 3.0 because she's 15th with
her last I have coming up oh yeah steady
last dive very consistent both Germans
consistently today there's the team
supporting them she's not the most
elegant of divers but she's certainly
very functional you've got up and down
into the water looking for the vertical
entry and there it is it's 3.0 mid-60s
and certainly a place in the semi-final
you should have your hair like that
didn't you marks for that dive 7.5 7
point 5 and 7 and 66 is the total score
for efficient ski Jennifer Abel who's
lived up to her name tonight she'll
finish off with a forward two and a half
somersaults with one twist
well Jennifer's not able to get on the
end of the diving board but she's very
able of completing the dive effortlessly
you start me off there Bob so here we go
into the end of the diving board
squeezing in so easy beautiful entry
into the water imagine if she was on the
end of the diving board she would have
got so much more height and made the
dive even easier eights across the board
- that's alright great dive very good in
fact 72 will get her up in the upper
stratosphere of this particular
competition and Limburg has a few little
difficulties but she's worked her way
into the top ten officially off for the
for two and a half with one twist the
pike position Oh little bit of
discrepancy entering the water net a
little bit slow on a rotation which
meant the completion of the dive was put
under pressure she wasn't quite straight
on the end as she went in here we go
squeezing into the Pike shape releasing
fitting in that one twist and as you can
see here Anna just running out
staying in a slight dished position as
she went in six is 6.5 s from the judges
I'm predicting let's see if your
prediction is true of course it's always
true 76.5 s for Anna Lindbergh the time
being up into third place you won't
remain there for very long nope Kristina
Lucas of the USA finishing off her
program eight after round four for two
and a half one twist in the pike
position again not wanting to get on the
end of the diving board obviously seems
some of the girls landing over the end
of the diving board
Lucas Blaney playing a little bit safe
on her approach there making the dive
tough yeah back from the end but such a
strong athlete very powerful and dynamic
able to get enough height and generate
enough rotation in order to complete the
dive very well indeed she'd have been up
in the 70s if she was on the end of the
diving board that's probably late 60s
now 60 7.50 to be precise that's all
right look overly chuffed about what
she's achieved today but she has
achieved a top 18 finish that's all she
needs now Sanchez Sato
that's their final dive forward two and
a half again yet two and a half with one
twist and that's probably know as best
I've to finish on there they take off
seem to be quite steady some of the
others she's been spinning sideways a
little bit towards the judges this one
looked pretty square on slightly back
from the end of the diving board there
but didn't seem to affect her that's a
really strong dive to finish on and
certainly secures a place going through
to the semis
Swayne for the marks to be confirmed and
they are now on your screen 7.5 s across
the board sixty seven point five zero
and she has moved up into the top four
but that will be a temporary position
could enough atop eighteen almost
certainly now let's dive from egg of
malaysia oh and she's finished on her
best i've only nineteen years old
invaluable experience here at the
olympic games she's been a bit here and
there throughout the program but at
least she's finished strongly this a
three point zero
he's got a lot of potential this girl
i'm sure we'll see her featuring again
and again on the way to rio just a
little over vertical as she went in as a
smile we've been waiting for as i must
smile about today but finally breaking
out into the room a grim 58.50 for the
malaysian tan yet can yato italy fishing
off reverse two-and-a-half with Mike
again three point zero
Oh fantastic dive this is Tonya's best
dive
she's as the European champion is their
fourth Olympic Games and she's got to
make the cut and I think she would be in
the top three she certainly was after
four rounds and that's a very very well
executed dive likely to get over 70
points beautiful splash let's entry into
the water how many marks well seventy
two yeah it's a very good reaction a
very good score for her and those three
eighths will take care right into the
upper echelon of this competition Chung
o Malaysia well suppose she's still an
outside chance a twenty first place of a
progression here so let's see what she
can do with this reverse one and a half
somersaults and to an hour of twists
what a beautiful dive Wow
very very neat and tidy it's almost a
classic dive this one one and a half
somersaults reverse with two and a half
twist here we are landing on the end
comes up here's the two and a half twist
only one and a half somersaults very
beautiful little bit of a discrepancy
there as she went into the water maybe
are some more fingernail and toes shots
there but let's have a look we're gonna
see another replay but no those are the
marks bit of a mixed bag six and a half
to eight and a half yeah I don't think I
should be worth more than 2.9 my
untrained idly I think - boy knows a bit
too bit mean on actually what you have
to do in terms of the execution of that
dive to get it in place but you know I'm
not the expert judges are Cassie Krug
finishing off with this now it's strong
start a little bit here and there in the
middle and a strong finish she's moved
down into where she was 12 after the
fourth round and that's a fantastic dive
to finish that will secure her a spot
you'll get over 70 points just I think
very strong diver very well executed and
welcome to the semi-finals yeah wishing
it all over again once you change your
program tomorrow as the program will see
from these divers again I think most of
them will keep it the same come the
marks eight eight right across the board
there that makes it an easy calculation
for you 24 times 3 makes 72 modesta
buzina russia in seventh place
and that'll be good enough to hold that
place definitely he's performed very
consistently today
Anastasia her business partner as in
teammate she'll have an agonizing wait
she hasn't been on a game
this Russian diver is on her game she'll
definitely be in the top ten she's done
her job this morning this afternoon I
mean that she'll be featuring again
tomorrow in the semi-final 60.9 zero
again nice calculation for you and 70s
on to chavez munos afraid she was the
bottom of the pile after round one and
she hasn't moved away from that sense
inward two and a half somersaults with
pike biggest I have to win the with oh
sure - vertical as she went in she's had
a tough day out there today only 21
years old at least experience of these
two Mexicans in the prelim here it's her
campaign closing right there so you take
some positives away great experience
competing against the world's very very
best and apart from a pretty disastrous
first round dive she stayed with it and
carried on trying hard great experience
soap and limpid games for her and she
will return as indeed will this diver as
he forward two and a half with one twist
to end off her
very impressive program
nor just letting the dive go over a
vertical her Z not completely on her
game today but she doesn't need to be
just an average performance we'll get
her through to the semi-finals easily
and this is probably her weakest I've of
the program today just over a vertical
as she goes in there having to roll to
try and save the dive to give the
impression to the judges that she's not
over a vertical in fact that they needed
to to be a little bit more sneaky than
that to confuse the judges let's see
what do they think they think 7s 1
thoughts there were two thoughts in
point five but they weren't count so 63
is the total marks for the Chinese
doesn't hang around does she forward two
and a half with one twist well that's
three out of the last three the federal
/ first two was shaky she's worked
tirelessly and very hard to get back in
contention
she was 14th after four rounds I think
that might sneak him up a little bit
which she'll be particularly pleased
with because she'll be making her way
through to the semi-final tomorrow yeah
for 14th greed now up into 12th position
for Elena feather over at 66 and she
will be part of the semi-final lineup
tomorrow
Castillo Suarez however will not again
just for Pride
she'll be hoping that the inward
two-and-a-half she's about to perform is
the best that she can do
oh she's finished on a good one
left herself too much to do 26 after the
the previous round of course top 18
going through to tomorrow's semi-final
but this the m-word standing backwards
spinning forwards towards a diving board
looking for that vertical entry little
bit over a vertical it'll get sevens and
that's a valiant effort final round dive
from the young Venezuelan only 21 years
old yeah give firm that she doesn't
qualify won't qualify in 19th place
they're three sevens goodbye it thank
you
now to Ming chef it was in first place
over the last round get to hold on to
that and Composition as she gets ready
for her back two-and-a-half somersaults
with Pike 3.0 for the Chinese yes
sensational Wow I think that is a little
hat tip to what's to come
those are the kind of dives that Wu has
in a diving Bank and that she can
withdraw them anytime and execute at
will that's near one perfect for me nine
point five s maybe even a ten if it was
a final I'm sure the judges would give
it a ten but this is prelims maybe
they're going to leave themselves
somewhere to go but that is near on
perfection from the Olympic champion in
the three metre synchro there you go
nine point five nine point five and 984
i think the biggest mark we've had today
for the chinese the raw greets rebecca
gallantry 16 after Round four she's seen
all this before that she hasn't seen it
with the 17 a half thousand people
screaming at her it's a home crowd
composure before Rebecca some can't
watch behind their fingers back two and
a half somersaults with Pike this for
progression just as Morrow semi-final oh
it's good that I think that'll be good
enough to get through to the semi-finals
Wow emotional stuff here in the Aquatic
Centre
Rebecca that's a solid performance good
last I allows herself a smile high
pressure out there today high
expectations for these British girls to
make it through to the semi-final was
their goal tipping over a vertical line
should be good enough for sevens which
will get him over 60 points which she
was in 16th from the previous round
should keep her in contention for going
through not that many divers left
fingers crossed for Rebecca gallantry
keep that smile on there 15th place for
Rebecca Allen treat this mence kept
hanging around no wanting to get that
dive lodged as soon as you can obviously
wants to go home maybe she's looking
forward to a dinner will she be coming
back for the semi finals tomorrow 22nd
after the fourth round I think that
might not be enough I have to wait and
see until all the divers have finished
and agonizing wait for some of these
competitors of course every single dive
counts that'll get sevens but sevens
probably won't be good enough back from
the end of the diving board makes it
tricky shame for the 2nd Ukrainian it's
no progression for his men Scott 19th
place is where she couldn't up could end
up a little bit low but you know top 18
place for her today nor for Fannie
Bouvet our France very low tariffs in
all of her dives includes this last one
2.7 might win an award for the costume
though in word two and a half
somersaults were tuck well she's
finished on her favorite dive again if
you look back at her performance it's
been pretty steady but as Bob mentioned
the degree of difficulty is very very
low on all of these dives she's only 18
years old looking to gain her Olympic
experience and she certainly got that
and it should be quite pleased with
their performance today to make through
to the semi-finals with a list of low
degree of difficulties a big ask and it
certainly won't be progressing funny
past the prelims
how she finished what scores she got
fifty one point three zero six point
five I'm sure we'll see Fanny again
Jennifer Benitez of Spain with her last
time and it will be her last time in
this competition Wow she hasn't had a
great day out there today
mrs. reverse one and a half somersaults
with one and a half twist it's only two
point five degree of difficulty so so
easy just landing on the end of the
diving board they're leaning back quite
a lot then you haven't you jump forward
in order to move clear of the diving
board yeah lots of little errors there
she's struggled today and won't be very
pleased without at all
twenty-seven just trying to find the
scoreboard
when I finally coach at the same time
time to go and get ready to go home
that's not what she came here to do nor
indeed does it mean for Giuliano Veloso
to be her last time in the competition
full-stop Giuliano really struggling
there some of these dyes are very very
difficult in fact all of the dyes she's
performed a very difficult this one in
particular three point one degree of
difficulty landing back from the end of
the diving board and that isn't very
good then she's got to squeeze into that
Pike shape you can see they're running
out of room landing shorter vertical
throwing up a load of splash that's
going to get a low low mark and there
you go 35 ouch
35 25 in terms of position in the
competition and she shall not be
returning for the last 18 jail Patrick
is in the very final position for
qualification saying this has to be
precise has to be good she's just taking
a little bit more time over this inward
two-and-a-half some margin between
thousand sixteen seventeen eighteen
nineteen and twenty was marginal before
she could underline her position in the
semis with this
well yeah it's a little bit low
finishing on the water it is up like
it's vertical the entry into the water
is neat and tidy she can squeeze six and
a half's and sevens from the judges on
this which I think she might well it's
gonna be close
he's gonna have to wait there's a couple
more divers to go just three more divers
to complete this so let's see I think
that might just be enough and we could
see more from jail as she goes through
to the semi colons aren't happy with
that overall performance
she should be much higher up than that
seventeenth now she hasn't qualified yet
Rebecca Gallen tree has kept giving her
what four starlings having to wait as
well she hasn't qualified yet the queue
hasn't come up beside her neighbors yet
but down up a feather over takeoff and
gallantry are through Nora barter she's
flirted with the top 18 she's been in
the top 18 December 25th here's a final
dime it's only worth two point eight in
terms of tariff projecting yourself on
the standings no that is a neat and tidy
dive instead back one and a half
somersaults with two and a half twists
only two point eight degree of
difficulty and we are wrapping into the
two and a half twists as she enters the
water here she's under twisted or
slightly over twisted which if the
judges spot that will penalize heavily
as we grab her hands as she goes in or a
tough day at the office I don't think
she will be progressing and no she won't
and that dive means that Hannah Starling
has made the semi-final she has the big
queue on our computer screen here to
indicate that she has made the last 18
Patrick is not as yes the Australians
just hanging on to wait and see whether
she gets into semi-finals
Emily Haman's it's been a model of
consistency today she fishes off a
program back two and a half yeah it's
good she'll progress through easily to
the semi-finals and of course all the
divers start from zero so it's the top
18 you will dive in reverse order it
will be a
Plus to tomorrow afternoon local time
and Emily Haman's already her medalist
here from these games in fact she's won
an Olympic medal at the Pratt past four
Olympic Games and she progresses through
to the semi-finals here are the marks
and they're good they're solid and then
consistent 7.5 coach is happy she's
happy and she will return for more in
the semi finals still up for grabs
terms the top 18 that's biggis flora
gone dose could do it she's got to make
a twenty point twenty point differential
though from 2.8 I don't think it's quite
gonna do it for a back one-and-a-half
somersaults two and a half twists choice
it's okay and as Bob mentioned it's only
2.8 back one and a half somersaults two
and a half twist she's certainly beating
her teammate today though this is gone
dose going for a last dive last-ditch
effort to get through to the semi-finals
it won't be enough with that tipping
over a vertical as she goes in so she'll
be going home well staying to watch the
rest of the Olympic Games she will not
be featuring in the semi-final there's
the confirmation so you had fun out
there today though bright future ahead
of it yeah we love you to Flora three
little star can shoot in the future for
the big names missed out kasnia cover
didn't make the top 18 she's the first
casualty both the British girls making
it through though with Rebecca Gallen
treat in 16th place and how Starling and
there they are
in 17th they have their anxious wait
they don't have the information that we
have on our computer system and they'll
see in a moment they play actually have
worked it out for themselves with just
in case here is confirmation China one
and two Italy Canada Australia so all
the big names getting through 387 the
top scorer there for whoo if the
Americans making it through the only
port Bates to the crowd have just seen
it and now you see it
16th Rebecca gantry 17th Vanna Starling
jail Patrick just getting in the last
position
anastasiya Pozniak over does not go
through big surprise there's any one
Russian involved those on the last page
kind of thanks for coming but no
progression for them so table 18 will
then turn into top 12 for semi-finals
that's all the big names with the
exception of Pozniak over are through to
the semi-finals there's the delight for
the home fans the home coaches and just
filtering out of the building now
looking quite happy your life Yong
Yong's Hanna starlings coach he's done
some great work there are the girls the
local girls well I say home giving the
crowd a wave I've never seen a crowd
this busy for a preliminary competition
in the diving fantastic support here
certainly lifted the girls here today
raising their game making it through to
the semi-final look at that sea of Union
Jack's everyone still here in the
building girls on their way over to the
mix own to do the interviews fantastic
effort still some improve is to be made
and of course only the top 12 make it
through from the semi-finals
so if gallantry and Starling want to
make it through they need to up their
game but rather that than the other way
so all to play for 24 hours to get ready
1430 British summer time we shall return
with the semi-finals top 18 whittled
down to top 12 in the women's 3-meter
springboard preliminary from Leon Taylor
myself Bob Ballard thank you for joining
us back with you again tomorrow
[Music]